Guide to the Ravi D. Goel Collection on Yale
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Ravi D. Goel collection on Yale
1714-2013
RU 1081
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.75
(3 boxes)
The collection consist of letters, postcards, photograph albums, and various printed ephemera documenting Yale affiliated individuals and organizations collected by Ravi D. Goel.
Goel, Ravi
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 45 (YRG 45), Yale objects and memorabilia.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ravi D. Goel (Yale College, 1993), 2008-2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
General
The collection was formerly titled Yale letters and memorabilia collection.
Scope and Contents
The collection consist of letters, postcards, photograph albums, and various printed ephemera documenting Yale affiliated individuals and organizations collected by Ravi D. Goel.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession, and chronologically therein.
College students -- Societies, etc.; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students; Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students
- Yale letters and memorabilia, 1823-1936; Accession 2008-A-176
  - R.S. Corring letter to Alder Scorch, 1823 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - E.A. Bradford (Yale 1833) letter to his mother Lois Bradford, 1833 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    The letter describes a visit to New Haven by President Jackson, Vice President Van Buren, Secretary of War Cass, Secretary of the Navy Woodbury, and Governor of New York Marcy.
  - Anthony D. Stanley (Yale 1830) letter recommending Osbert Burr Loomis (Yale 1835) for a position in the Department of Sciences, 1835 April (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Joanna B., Mrs., letter to George Duffield (Yale 1837), 1837 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Topics include a Hymn, religion, the King of England, and marriage.
  - William Pierce Eaton (Yale 1837) letter to William H. Tiffany (Yale 1840) regarding Kingsley's oration, 1838 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer Wyllys Warner (Yale 1826) letter to Aaron Kellog about indigent student fund, 1843 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - J.R.W. Pitt? letter to his uncle Eccleston, 1845 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Topics include Princeton Cliosophic Society, various Yale professors, and religion.
  - "Man is a responsible being" student essay, 1847 September (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Edward Warren Bentley (Yale 1850) letter to Elisha Manross, 1847 October 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Correspondence regarding illness of Newton Spaulding Manross (1850). Post-script by Newton Manross to mother.
  - Yung Wing (Yale 1854) letter to Albert Booth (Yale 1850), 1851 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    First Chinese student writes of student life, Munson Academy, and "The many disadvantages with which I labor."
  - Envelope addressed to president Theodore D. Woolsey (Yale 1820), 1853 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Presentation of the wooden spoon program, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Wooden spoon exhibition invitation, 1854 June (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "A season of exuberant beauty" (poem) by Professor Benjamin Silliman, Jr. (Yale 1837), 1857 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Wallace M. Smith letter to Tracy Peck, Jr. (Yale 1861), 1859 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Item regarding oration delivered before the Society of BB's in Bristol.
  - Heman Potter Babcock letter to Tracy Peck, Jr. (Yale 1861), 1860 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Topics include student life and Skull and Bones symbol.
  - Latin phrase/sentence signed President Theodore D. Woolsey (Yale 1820), 1860 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Envelope addressed to John W. Sterling from "Kate and father", 1861 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Edward F. Blake (Yale 1858) letter to Thomas D. Kimball, 1861 February 14 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Wooden spoon exhibition invitation and ticket, 1869-1870 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Skull and Bones letters, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Multiple letters from the Skull and Bones Delegation of 1874 to Thomas P. Wickes (1874).
  - Timothy Dwight letter to Mr. Mosman, 1878 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Charley [last name unknown] (Yale 1894?), Yale student, letters to parents, 1891 January-November; Consists of 11 letters. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Timothy Dwight letter to Henry Pavet, 1894 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Correspondence regarding scarce autograph and "eyes were in a delicate condition" of 1st president Timothy Dwight (1769).
  - Sheffield Scientific School Class of 1877 twentieth reunion dinner menu signed by numerous members of class, 1897 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "The One-Time Wooden Spoon at Yale," by Miles G. Hyde (Yale 1865), Circa 1899 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Includes gift 1899 inscription from 1863 winner G.C.S. Southworth to daughter.
  - Professor William Beebe (Yale 1873) letter to Mr. Welch (Yale 1902), 1901 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Item regarding Yale Literary Magazine and canvassing of freshman class for campus publications.
  - Edward A. Bouchet (Yale 1874) postcard to James F. Alston, 1911 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Topics include Alumni Hall and construction of Wright Memorial Dormitory.
  - Scroll and Key photograph album, Delegation, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Scroll and Key postcard from Henry Tomlinson Curtis (Yale 1910) to Joseph Curtis Platt (Yale 1910) regarding name change of Kingsley Trust Association, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "A Letter from a Father to His Son," by John D. Swain, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Yale University commencement bulletin, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Arthur Twining Hadley (Yale 1876), former Yale president, letter to Mrs. Sloane, widow of lifelong friend William Mulligan Sloane, 1928 September 26 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Willie Bronkie (Sheffield 1933) letters concerning football, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Yale Whiffenpoof Song (Advance Artist Copy), 1936 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Averell Harriman (Yale 1913), Secretary, US Dept. of Commerce and Chairman, All-Yale Committee to Rebuild Yale-In-China, letter to Daniel Rochford, 1947 December 17 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Yale letters and memorabilia, 1714-1912; Accession 2012-A-014
  - List of contents with detailed descriptions by Ravi D. Goel, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Josiah Willard (Yale 1714) letter to unnamed recipient, 1719 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Samuel Cowles deed signed by Oliver Partridge (Yale 1730), 1734 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Timothy Cutler letter to Sir Geflow Cambridge, 1736 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Letter to Cambridge University colleague (President?) regarding his son and which college he will chose to go to; Christopher Bridge a recent graduate of Harvard, enjoying some Madeira wine, the comments of Sir Isaac Newton and procurement of books from a fellow at Eton College.
  - Mary Welch indenture document signed by David Lee and Ebenezer Gray, 1744 December 31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    The doument concerns the indenture of Mary Welch, an 8 year old poor female whose father, Jonathan Welch of Lebanon, is deceased. Mary is to be a Maid Servant or Apprentice to David Lee (1674 - 1759) and his wife of Coventry, Connecticut, until she reached the age of 18. Document stipulates Mary's duties and the moral behavior by which she must abide. The document further stipulates the obligations of the Lee family to provide well for Mary, to teach her to read, sew, and to perform the tasks of a Maid Servant, which consisted of standard housekeeping tasks of the day.
    Jonathan Trumble [Trumbull] is mentioned in the document.
  - Jacob Heminway (Yale 1704) quit claim, 1746 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jabez Huntington (Yale 1741) letter to Joseph Talcut (Talcott), 1765 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aaron Hutchinson (Yale 1747) letter of complaint from congregation, 1770 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Isaac Backus deed of sale of land to Elijah Backus, signed by Benjamin Huntington (Yale 1761) as registrar, 1773 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Benjamin Stiles (Yale 1740) writ of summons, 1775 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Abraham Davenport signed receipt (as selectman) of reimbursement from state for purchase of supplies for soldiers by Stamford, 1778 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Henry Daggett (Yale 1775) receipt for camp equipment, 1779 September (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Oliver Wolcott, Jr. (Yale 1773) signed pay voucher, 1783 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - John Hobart (Yale 1757) court order, 1785 September 29 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Jonathan Trumbull, Jr. and Eliphalet Dyer document concerning Joseph Trumbull's estate, 1788 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Augustine Taylor (Yale 1776) letter to State of Connecticut, 1790 August (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Enoch Woodbridge (Yale 1774) court warrant, 1795 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    General
    This is a copy of the original warrant dated 1794 Nov 19, with an addition.
  - Oliver Wolcott, Jr. (Yale 1773) acknowledgment of Customs payment, 1794 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - John Porter (Yale 1776) statement issued as Comptroller to Samuel Wyllis regarding overcharges, 1796 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Horace Holley (Yale 1803) letters to father, Luther Holley
    - 1799 December 26 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1800 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1800 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1802 February 14 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - James Hillhouse (Yale 1773) letter to Jeremiah Wadsworth, 1802 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Reverend Samuel Haskell (Yale 1790) letter to Reverend Parker, 1804 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - John Davenport (Yale 1770) letter to Governor John Treadwell, 1810 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Frederick F. Backus (Yale 1813, Medical 1816) letter to Azel Backus, 1815 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Abraham Winchell letter to Isaac Bird, 1817 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - William Sullivant (Yale 1823) agreement to sell land to William W. Haines, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Sutherland Douglas (Yale 1822) letter to Alanson Douglas, 1827 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - D. Buel to Thomas Hubbard (Yale 1799), 1827 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Joshua T. Eaton (Yale 1830) letter to Lawson Buckminster, 1828 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Thomas W. Coit (Yale 1821) letter of resignation to St. Peter's Church, Salem, 1829 March 16 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bennett Bronson (Yale 1797) letter to Leonard Bacon, 1831 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Chauncey Goodrich (Yale 1837) letter to Edward Ellsworth, 1831 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Jeremiah Day (Yale 1795) letter of thanks for donation, 1835 August 4 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Elial T. Foote letter to Thomas H. Hubbard (Yale 1799), 1836 August 16 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - S. Meylert letter to Samuel A. Law (Yale 1792), 1839 January 5 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Oliver P. Hubbard (Yale 1828) to Faith Hubbard, 1842 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Edward Rogers letter to Thomas Hubbard (Yale 1799) concerning Hezekiah Gold Rogers (Yale 1831), 1846 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Jeremiah Day (Yale 1795) invitation to General Associations Committee meeting, 1846 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Daniel P. Noyes (Yale 1840) letter to father, Daniel Noyes, 1847 March 22 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Samuel Selden letter to Benjamin Ely (Yale 1786) concerning George Selden (Yale 1786), 1848 July 26 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Orin Fowler (Yale 1814) letter to Captain John Sanford, Circa 1850 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Edward E. Salisbury (Yale 1832) letter to N. F. Graves, 1852 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - President Theodore Woolsey (Yale 1820) letter to W. Alfred Jones, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - William H. Anderson (Yale 1859) letters to S. G. Haley
    - 1858 June 4 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - 1858 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Charles Clarke (Yale 1809) agreement to purchase property, 1861 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Edward J. Phelps letters to George Washington Harman regarding legal matters
    - 1864 January 2-5 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - 1865 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - 1865 July 8-10 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - 1866 July 7-9 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - 1869 April 24-26 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - 1869 May 3-4 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - 1869 September 29-30 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - 1869 October 11-13 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - 1869 November 7-9 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - 1869 November 14-19 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Horace Bushnell (1827) letter to G. B. Bacon, 1867 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Alexander R. Merriman (Yale 1872) letter to brother Henry, 1869 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Alexander R. Merriman (Yale 1872) letter to "Dear Fannie", 1870 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - President Theodore Woolsey (Yale 1820) letter to Reverend Doctor Lawrence, 1870 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Benjamin Silliman, Jr. (Yale 1837) letter to Platt Potter, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Noah Porter (Yale 1831) letter to his brother, Circa 1851-1873 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Noah Porter (Yale 1831) letter to Mrs. Huntington, 1885 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Theodore W. Dwight (Yale Law 1845) letter to Dorman B. Eaton, 1887 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Timothy Dwight (Yale 1849) letter to the Committee of Plymouth Church and Society, 1890 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - William Howard Taft (Noah Porter (Yale 1878) letter to Fred Percy, 1898 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Helen Holbrook letter to Mr. Sawyer, 1908 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Contains references to Harvard President Eliot and Theodore Roosevelt contretemps.
  - William Howard Taft (Yale 1878) letter to Bishop William A. Leonard, 1912 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Yale letters and memorabilia, 1743-1981, 2013; Accession 2013-A-053
  - List of contents with detailed descriptions by Ravi D. Goel, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jonathan Trumble (Trumbull) document from court of Justice Isaac Huntington, 1743 August 23 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Document from the court of Justice Isaac Huntington of Norwich, Connecticut. Signed by Revolutionary War patriot Jonathan Trumble [Trumbull] with the form of spelling in use for the family's name until 1766. This document was sent to the Sheriff of New London County ordering him to summon Joshua Woodworth to court to answer to Thomas Danforth for debts owed. Sheriff's deposition and account of court costs on reverse.
  - Ebenezer Silliman (Yale 1727) directive to Nathaniel Stanley, 1753 March 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    The letter directs Stanley to issue payment due to Daniel Edwards (Yale 1725)
  - Thaddeus Betts (Yale 1745), Justice of the Peace in Norwalk, letter to Treasurer of State of Connecticut, 1777 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Abatement of 63 pounds is issued for overtaxation in 1776.
  - Eleazer Wheelock (Yale 1733), President of Dartmouth, agreement with Mr. John Smith as first professor, 1777 November 9, 1778 August 27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Copy from the original; date copy made is unknown.
  - Jonathan Walter Edwards (Yale 1789) letter to "Brother Nathan", 1796 March 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    The letter concerns matrimony.
  - Charles Backus (Yale 1769) letter to Henry Davis, Tutor at Yale, 1799 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Elizur Goodrich (Yale 1779), Probate Court Judge for New Haven, legal document, 1809 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    The document appoints William M'Cracken and Nathan Smith as executors for William M'Cracken's estate.
  - Litchfield County legal document on Lenar Hayes versus John Skinner, 1810 January 24 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    The document concerns Hopkins Farm in New Hartford, signed by John Trumbull (Yale 1767), Superior Court Judge.
  - President Jeremiah Day (Yale 1795) letter to Samuel Gardiner (Yale 1835), expressing thanks for gift of book, 1839 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - John Law (Yale 1814) letter to Levi Woodbury, 1845 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    The letter concerns political issues.
  - C. H. Carter [?] letter to Albert Booth (Yale 1850), 1849 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    In the letter Carter discusses his problems at Brown University.
  - Acknowledgment of gift of book from Roger S. Baldwin (Yale 1811), signed by President Theodore Woolsey (Yale 1820) and Librarian E. C. Herrick, 1853 May (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - J. J. Edic (Yale 1864) letter to his brother, 1861 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Contains a brief mention of classmate (Thomas Carolin Clay) who "left yesterday on account of the secession he was from Georgia"; rest of letter relates issues of daily life.
  - Timothy Dwight letter to Professor Hewitt, 1875 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    In the letter Dwight asks Hewitt to preach at the First Congregational Church of Milford in August.
  - Theodore Dwight Woolsey (Yale 1820) letter to Carl Stoeckel, 1885 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Woolsey discusses a book missing from his personal library (Edward Buck's "Massachusetts ecclesiastical law" (1866) and the inability of colonial ministers to unite a couple in marriage and the post-1700 law allowing ministers to unite, with magistrates present.
  - Timothy Dwight (Yale 1849) condolence letter to Mrs. Littleton P. Franklin, 1888 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Condolence letter from Yale President Timothy Dwight to the widow of his classmate Littleton P. Franklin (Yale 1849). Dwight writes of remembering his classmate from college days.
  - Timothy Dwight (Yale 1849) letter to Mrs. Littleton P. Franklin, 1889 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Letter from Yale President Timothy Dwight to the widow of his classmate Littleton P. Franklin (Yale 1849), in which Dwight requestsfor biographical information for upcoming 40th reunion of the Yale Class of 1849.
  - Poultney Bigelow (Yale 1879) essay, 1889; tamped "Revue de Famille -- La Vie Contemporaine" on first page. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Charles Rockwell Lanman (Yale 1871) letter to John Ritchie, Jr., declining invitation, 1904 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - President-elect William Howard Taft (Yale 1878) thank-you letter to Major William L. Kneedler, 1908 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - William H. Welch (Yale 1870) letter to niece Bessie Kellogg, with thanks for Christmas gift, 1911 December 23 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Supreme Court Chief Justice William Howard Taft (Yale 1878) letter to Richard Washburn Child, American Ambassador, Rome, introducing two sisters-in-law, 1921 August 24 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Edwin A. Burtt (Yale 1915) letter to A. H. Wagner, 1937 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Letter, with envelope, breifly discussing question of immortality.
  - Selden Rodman letter to Atwood H. Townsend concerning "American Brotherhood" prospectus, 1942 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Henry L. Stimson (Yale 1888) letter to Ashley T. Cole, 1948 July 19 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Stimson acknowledges interest in his recent book "On Active Service" and sends along slip of paper with inscription.
  - Autographed copy of Dean Acheson's address, "Real and Imagined Handicaps of Our Democracy in the Conduct of Its Foreign Relations", 1962 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - W. Averill Harriman (Yale 1913) letter to Robert B. Greenes urging support of Senator Quentin N. Burdick, 1970 June 3 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Justice Byron R. White (Yale Law 1946) letter to Eugene C. Gerhart, Editor in Chief, New York State Bar Journal, granting permission to reprint article, 1981 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 29)